Joan Carlos Rosario

Senior Software Engineer

Profile

Sr. Full Stack Developer with 7 years of hands on experience in creating and implementing Web and Mobile solutions. I look forward to bringing my strong creative, technical and analytics skills in a proactive manner for enterprises and customer service.

Contact information

joancarlosrosarios@gmail.com



1-849-344-9773



Santo Domingo, R.D.



www.linkedin.com/in/joan-carlos-rosario-de-la-rosa

Skills

Java Angular SQL **AWS CSS** React

Idioms

English

Spanish

Experience

React - Java Developer 2021 Now

2021 - Today - Encora

- Responsible for migration of complete API using Spring Cloud.
- Creation of SQL scripts for database implementation.
- Creation of several endpoints using microservice architecture pattern, using Junit and spring annotations.
- Implement the use of AWS services like lambda functions using
- Using methodologies like Scrum.
- Use of GIT / JIRA/ Confluence.
- Creation of Microservice using Kubernetes configuration for deployment
- Integration of database using docker images.

Angular - Java Developer

2019 - 2021 - BairesDev

- Creation of several endpoints using microservice architecture pattern.
- Expertise in Angular framework and its ability to create simple and scalable code for SPA.
- Creation of reusable components using Angular, Cypress, Pact, lest.

Angular Java Developer - Co-lead

- 2017 2019 Newtech Verizon
- Responsible of the migration of complete modules using REST / API using the best practices and takes care of the performance.
- Experience in security validation using captcha and OAuth token.
- Contributed to the in-house reusable components that saves development time and effort.

PHP - Javascript Developer

- 2015 2017 Newtech
- Design and implement new features from scratch using pure JavaScript.
- Design responsive UI using CSS3 and HTML5 with mobile and web support.
- Manage Business logic using MVC design patterns.
- Prepared stored procedures and T-SQL queries from sources of MS SQL server databases

Education

Bachelor's Degree in computer science

Universidad Tecnológica de Santiago 2007 –2016

Informatic Technician

Instituto Politécnico Cardenal Sancha 2003 – 2007